J. Raymond Quirke

53 Fitzroy Avenue, Drumcondra, Dublin 3 Tel: 086 - 4097598

E-mail: jraymondquirke@gmail.com Linked-In: www.linkedin.com/in/raymond-quirke

Professional Profile

NEBOSH qualified EHS Lead with over 8 years' pharmaceutical industry experience successfully implemented EHS plans and initiatives across eight departments. As an accomplished EHS professional skilled at designing and implementing an effective EHS management system alongside driving cultural change, safety awareness, training and risk assessment programs through toolbox talks and safety audits. Have a genuine passion for personnel safety and achieved goals resulting in an effective EHS culture.

Key Skills

- Policy and Procedure Management
- Risk Assessment
- Critical Thinker & Problem Solver
- **Accident Prevention**

- NEBOSH Certificate in Occ. Health & Safety
- Certified Machinery Safety Expert
- Degree qualified in Structural Engineering
- Post-graduate Diploma in Project Management

Employment Record

Position: EHS Lead Jan 2015 to Present Tosara Pharma Ltd., Part of the TEVA Group

Working as EHS Lead for a manufacturing pharmaceutical company in Baldoyle, Dublin 13 specialising in the manufacture of an OTC product Sudocrem, implementing policy and procedures, EHS KPIs and advising 8no. Department Managers to 175no. employees and directly reporting to both Site General Manager and to offsite Global Sr. Director EHS Europe ensuring EHS compliance.

Responsibilities:

- Develop, implement, review and update the health and safety management system and policy.
- Support regulatory and global EHS audits addressing observations and findings through CAPA system.
- Liaise regularly with management and global EHS to implement best practices across the industry.
- Consult technical SMEs and provide support for processes, communications, training and systems.
- Work proactively with managers and employees to ensure the company meets its statutory obligations.
- Maintain accurate up-to-date accident and 'near miss' log ensuring all accidents are investigated.
- Inform the HSA of all accidents or incidents that require notification and support HR regarding claims.
- Carry out regular safety inspections, fire drills, risk assessment updates and review of procedures.
- Effectively communicate to employees through gemba walks, toolbox talks and team brief meetings.

Achievements:

- Implemented an EHS management system from zero (30no. procedures) to comply with ISO45001.
- Reduced the serious injury incident rate from 6.08 to 1.22 reaching 'target zero' for a 3 year period.
- Reduced control hazards by 37%, by performing audits & implementing a hazard observation program.
- Implemented 6no. safe work permit programs & achieved an audit CAPA closure rate >95% annually.

Tosara Pharma Ltd., Part of the TEVA Group **Position: Validation Projects Engineer** Responsibilities:

Aug 2012 to Dec 2014

Chaired Project Teams and communicated progress reports, minutes, lessons learnt and costs realized.

- Coordinated Contractors, drafted pricing tender documents and evaluated tenders.
- Produced and executed URS/FAT/SAT/IQ/OQ/PQ commissioning and qualification documents.
- Organized and implemented service level agreements and as-built system drawings.

Achievements:

Successfully oversaw, led and executed 7no. CQV projects some which include a new compressed air system, upgrades to production lines with all tracked to be on time and ensured project programmes were completed to meet GMP Quality requirements and were within budget.

Employment Record cont'd

Carillion Energy Services, EAGA Ireland Position: Engineer Energy Assessor & Surveyor

May 2010 to Dec 2011

Responsibilities:

- Orchestrated and planned surveys to domestic houses (Home Energy Saving Scheme).
- Drafted reports, compiled applications and coordinated contractors regarding all home energy upgrades.

Achievements:

Successfully managed >2,510no. homeowner projects throughout Munster and Leinster regions.

Fearon O'Neill Rooney, Consulting Engineers

Oct 1999 to July 2009

Position: Projects Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Acted as Project Supervisor Design Process (PSDP) addressing all project H&S needs.
- Supervised, mentored, delegated priorities & set goals for Design Engineers/CAD Technicians.
- Managed structural and technical design services from scheme to detailed design to various projects.
- Coordinated structural drawing preparation, specifications and contract documentation.
- Implemented H&S plans, tender specifications, scope of works, BOQs, schedule of dilapidations & EIAs.
- Liaised with contractors to timely address RFIs, deficiencies and design plans to rectify them.
- Communicated to Design Team progress reports, meeting minutes, lessons learnt & costs realized.

Achievements:

- Provided technical design services & structural analysis to projects from €0.3 to €10.3m some include:
 - o Chambers Court, Value €0.3million Demolition of 3No. five storey Apartment blocks, pile cut offs.
 - o **Bow Lane**, Value €5million Five storey hostel, refurbishment of existing 18th century listed building.
 - o **Annesley Bridge**, Value €1.5million Conservation & refurbishment of 20th century 3 span bridge.
 - o **St. Josephs College,** Value €7.5million Two storey extension, civil works to adjoining public-park.
 - o Cork Street, Value €10.3million 4No. Apartment blocks & piles/ground beams over archaeology.
 - Wexford Hospital, Value €6million Steel portal frames, ground beams, 50No. 100-150 tonne piles.
 - o No. 12 & 13 Leeson Park, Dublin 2, Value €2.5million Refurbishment works to Victorian buildings.
 - o Swords Fire Station, Value €2.5million New Station Building & 4 storey fire tower.
- Successfully acted as health & safety PSDP on several projects with a clear health and safety record.
- Provided design services to foul & surface drainage including attenuation design using SuDS.
- Successfully implemented projects for the Client, 95% completed on time and within budget.

Educational & Training Records

•	First Aider, Manual Handling Instructor, MEWP & Certified Machinery Safety Expert	2023
•	Chemical Awareness, Dangerous Goods, Fire Marshall & Manual Handling Certification	2021-2022
•	NeBOSH Certificate in Occupational Health & Safety	2015-2016
•	Commissioning & Qualification of Systems & Fundamentals of Pharmaceutical Technologies	2012
•	Diploma in Project Management, Trinity College Dublin	2010-2011
•	Bachelor of Science in Structural Engineering, Trinity College (Honours Degree)	1994-1998
•	Diploma in Structural Engineering, DIT Bolton St., (Honours Diploma)	1994-1998

Computer Skills, Interests & Personnel Information

- Microsoft Office including MS Project, Excel, Word, Outlook, Powerpoint. Excellent with AutoCAD, design packages Masterseries, SCALE, FEA modeling using STRAP, drainage design using WinDES
- I enjoy keeping fit, cycling, jogging, pitch & putt, DIY, Photography & travelling to explore other cultures.
- Full clean driver's license

References

References available on request.